

TS/SCI Cleared | (803)507-0114 | awardnasc@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/alex-w96

SUMMARY

Software Engineer and leader with experience designing and developing offensive cyber weapons and 2 years of experience leading teams of 10 people to award-winning product deliveries. Broad technical expertise across modern web, low power computing, and windows development. Excellent verbal and written communication skills. Continuous learner with the ability to quickly become productive in new languages and tools.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

May 2021 - Present

Executive Officer, 318 Cyberspace Operations Group, San Antonio, TX

- Competitively selected for leadership development position, #1/41 1st Lieutenants.
- Leveraged software development expertise to craft data flows exposing information from legacy systems into real-time dashboards that enable data-driven decision making.

July 2019 - May 2021

Software Developer and Team Lead, 90 Cyberspace Operations Squadron, San Antonio, TX

- Led an Agile team of 10 developers creating Linux cyberspace operations tools. Named ACC Superior Performer and #1/8 Military Developers.
- Implemented multiple continuous improvement initiatives to boost an underperforming team,
 resulting in the award of #1 Small Team of the Year at the group level.
- Designed and developed DoD's first extensible distributed attack platform capable of coordinating 8,000+ simultaneous strikes.
 - Technology: C, Javascript, Python, React, Redux, Jest, Flask, MongoDB, Protocol Buffers, Docker, Gitlab CI
- Extended network operations platform by integrating exploits for 10 new network devices.
 Resolved critical mission stoppage of \$325M platform used for presidential election defense.
 - o **Technology**: Python, Docker, Openstack, Gitlab CI

June 2018 - August 2018 & June 2017 - August 2017

Software Engineering Intern, The Home Depot, Atlanta, GA

- Developed and deployed two web applications to production. Received full-time job offer on completion.
 - Technology: Javascript, Java, Go, Angular, React, Spring Boot, Maven, Mockito, Pivotal Cloud Foundry, Pivotal Concourse, Drone Cl, Google Natural Language and Vision APIs

EDUCATION

2019 - Present

Georgia Institute of Technology | MS, Computer Science, 4.0 GPA

2018 - 2019

The United States Air Force Undergraduate Cyber Training | Distinguished Graduate (#2/16), 98% GPA 2014 - 2018

Clemson University | BS, Computer Science, Minor in Aerospace Studies